What is the LLM model?
什么是法学硕士模式？
Sometimes people think of a large language model as a knowledge store,
有时人们将大型语言模型视为知识存储，
as if it learns to memorize a lot of information, maybe off the internet,
好像它学会了记住很多信息，也许是在互联网上，
so when you ask it a question, it can answer the question.
所以当你问它一个问题时，它可以回答这个问题。
But I think an even more useful way to think of a large language model
但我认为一种更有用的方法来思考大型语言模型
is sometimes as a reasoning engine, in which you can give it chunks of text
有时作为推理引擎，您可以在其中为其提供文本块
or other sources of information.
或其他信息来源。
And then the large language model, LLM, will maybe use this background knowledge
然后大型语言模型LLM可能会使用这种背景知识。
that is learned off the internet, but to use the new information you give it
这是从互联网上学到的，但要使用您提供的新信息
to help you answer questions or reason through content or decide even what to do next.
帮助您通过内容回答问题或推理，甚至决定下一步该做什么。
And that's what LLM Chain's Agents framework hopes you to do.
这就是LLM Chain的代理框架希望你做的。
Agents are probably my favorite part of LLM Chain.
代理商可能是我最喜欢的LLM链部分。
I think they're also one of the most powerful parts,
我认为它们也是最强大的部分之一，
but they're also one of the newer parts.
但它们也是较新的部分之一。
So we're seeing a lot of stuff emerge here that's really new to everyone in the field.
所以我们看到这里出现了很多东西，对这个领域的每个人都是全新的。
And so this should be a very exciting lesson as we dive into what agents are,
因此，当我们深入研究代理是什么时，这应该是一个非常令人兴奋的课程，
how to create and how to use agents, how to equip them with different types of tools,
如何创建和如何使用代理，如何为它们配备不同类型的工具，
like search engines that come built into LLM Chain,
就像内置在LLM链中的搜索引擎一样，
and then also how to create your own tools so that you can let agents interact
然后是如何创建自己的工具，以便您可以让代理进行交互
with any data stores, any APIs, any functions that you might want them to.
使用任何数据存储、任何 API、您可能希望它们使用的任何功能。
So this is exciting, cutting-edge stuff, but already with emerging important use cases.
所以这是令人兴奋的尖端东西，但已经出现了重要的用例。
So with that, let's dive in.
因此，让我们深入了解。
First, we're going to set the environment variables and import a bunch of stuff
首先，我们将设置环境变量并导入一堆东西
that we will use later on.
我们稍后会使用。
Next, we're going to initialize a language model.
接下来，我们将初始化一个语言模型。
We're going to use chat open AI, and importantly,
我们将使用聊天开放AI，重要的是，
we're going to set the temperature equal to zero.
我们将温度设置为零。
This is important because we're going to be using the language model
这很重要，因为我们将使用语言模型。
as the reasoning engine of an agent where it's connecting
作为代理连接的推理引擎
to other sources of data and computation.
到其他数据和计算来源。
And so we want this reasoning engine to be as good and as precise as possible,
所以我们希望这个推理引擎尽可能好和精确，
and so we're going to set it to zero to get rid of any randomness that might arise.
因此，我们将它设置为零，以消除可能出现的任何随机性。
Next, we're going to load some tools.
接下来，我们将加载一些工具。
The two tools that we're going to load are the LLM Math tool and the Wikipedia tool.
我们将要加载的两个工具是LLM数学工具和维基百科工具。
The LLM Math tool is actually a chain itself, which uses a language model
LLM数学工具实际上本身就是一个链，它使用语言模型
in conjunction with a calculator to do math problems.
与计算器结合使用来做数学题。
The Wikipedia tool is an API that connects to Wikipedia,
维基百科工具是一个连接到维基百科的API，
allowing you to run search queries against Wikipedia and get back results.
允许您对维基百科运行搜索查询并获取结果。
Next, we're going to initialize an agent.
接下来，我们将初始化一个代理。
We're going to initialize the agent with the tools, the language model,
我们将使用工具、语言模型、
and then an agent type.
然后是代理类型。
Here, we're going to use chat zero shot react description.
在这里，我们将使用聊天零镜头反应描述。
The important things to note here are first, chat.
这里要注意的重要事项首先是聊天。
This is an agent that has been optimized to work with chat models.
这是一个经过优化以使用聊天模型的代理。
And second, react.
其次，做出反应。
This is a prompting technique designed to get the best reasoning performance
这是一种提示技术，旨在获得最佳推理性能
out of language models.
语言模型之外。
We're also going to pass in handle parsing errors equals true.
我们还将传入句柄解析错误等于 true。
This is useful when the language model might output something that is not able
当语言模型可能输出无法输出的内容时，这很有用
to be parsed into an action and action input, which is the desired output.
解析为操作和操作输入，这是所需的输出。
When this happens, we'll actually pass the misformatted text back
发生这种情况时，我们实际上会将格式错误的文本传回
to the language model and ask it to correct itself.
到语言模型并要求它自行更正。
And finally, we're going to pass in verbose equals true.
最后，我们将传递详细等于 true。
This is going to print out a bunch of steps that makes it really clear to us
这将打印出一堆步骤，使我们非常清楚。
in the Jupyter Notebook what's going on.
在Jupyter笔记本中发生了什么。
We'll also set debug equals true at the global level later on in the notebook
稍后，我们还将在笔记本中在全局级别设置 debug 等于 true。
so we can see in more detail what exactly is happening.
因此，我们可以更详细地了解究竟发生了什么。
First, we're going to ask the agent a math question.
首先，我们要问代理一个数学问题。
What is 25% of 300?
25 的 300% 是多少？
This is a pretty simple question, but it will be good to understand
这是一个非常简单的问题，但最好理解
what exactly is going on.
到底是怎么回事。
We can see here that when it enters the agent executor chain,
我们在这里可以看到，当它进入代理执行器链时，
that it first thinks about what it needs to do.
它首先考虑它需要做什么。
It has a thought.
它有一个想法。
It then has an action, and this action is actually a JSON blob
然后它有一个操作，这个操作实际上是一个 JSON blob
corresponding to two things, an action and an action input.
对应于两件事，一个动作和一个动作输入。
The action corresponds to the tool to use.
该操作对应于要使用的工具。
Here it says calculator.
这里说计算器。
The action input is the input to that tool.
操作输入是该工具的输入。
Here it's a string of 300 times .25.
这是一串 300 乘以 .25。
Next, we can see that there's observation with answer in a separate color.
接下来，我们可以看到有单独颜色的观察和答案。
This observation, answer equals 75.0, is actually coming from
这个观察，答案等于75.0，实际上是来自
the calculator tool itself.
计算器工具本身。
Next, we go back to the language model when the text turns to green.
接下来，当文本变为绿色时，我们返回到语言模型。
We have the answer to the question.
我们有问题的答案。
Final answer, 75.0, and that's the output that we get.
最终答案，75.0，这就是我们得到的输出。
This is a good time to pause and try out different math problems of your own.
这是暂停并尝试自己的不同数学问题的好时机。
Next, we're going to go through an example using the Wikipedia API.
接下来，我们将通过一个使用维基百科API的示例。
Here we're going to ask it a question about Tom Mitchell,
在这里，我们要问一个关于汤姆·米切尔的问题，
and we can look at the intermediate steps to see what it does.
我们可以看看中间步骤，看看它的作用。
We can see once again that it thinks and it correctly realizes
我们可以再次看到它思考并正确地意识到
that it should use Wikipedia.
它应该使用维基百科。
It says action equal to Wikipedia and action input equal to Tom M. Mitchell.
它说动作等于维基百科，动作输入等于汤姆·米切尔。
The observation that comes back in yellow this time,
这次以黄色返回的观察结果，
and we use different colors to denote different tools,
我们使用不同的颜色来表示不同的工具，
is the Wikipedia summary result for the Tom M. Mitchell page.
是汤姆·米切尔页面的维基百科摘要结果。
The observation that comes back from Wikipedia is actually two results,
从维基百科回来的观察结果实际上是两个结果，
two pages, as there's two different Tom M. Mitchells.
两页，因为有两个不同的汤姆·
We can see the first one covers the computer scientist,
我们可以看到第一个涵盖了计算机科学家，
and the second one, it looks like it's an Australian footballer.
第二个，看起来像是澳大利亚足球运动员。
We can see that the information needed to answer this question,
我们可以看到回答这个问题所需的信息，
namely the name of the book that he wrote, Machine Learning,
即他写的书的名字，机器学习，
is present in the summary of the first Tom M. Mitchell.
出现在第一部汤姆·
We can see next that the agent tries to look up more information about this book.
接下来我们可以看到，代理试图查找有关本书的更多信息。
He looks up Machine Learning book in Wikipedia.
他在维基百科上查找机器学习书籍。
This isn't strictly necessary, and it's an interesting example
这不是绝对必要的，这是一个有趣的例子
to show how agents aren't perfectly reliable yet.
以显示代理如何还不完全可靠。
We can see that after this lookup, the agent recognizes that it has
我们可以看到，在这次查找之后，代理认识到它有
all the information it needs to answer and responds with the correct answer,
它需要回答的所有信息，并以正确的答案回应，
Machine Learning.
机器学习。
The next example we're going to go through is a really cool one.
我们将要经历的下一个示例是一个非常酷的示例。
If you've seen things like Copilot or even ChatGPT
如果你见过Copilot甚至ChatGPT之类的东西。
with the code interpreter plug-in enabled,
启用代码解释器插件后，
one of the things they're doing is they're using the language model
他们正在做的一件事是他们正在使用语言模型。
to write code and then executing that code.
编写代码，然后执行该代码。
We can do the same exact thing here.
我们可以在这里做同样的事情。
We're going to create a Python agent, and we're going to use the same LLM
我们将创建一个Python代理，我们将使用相同的LLM
as before, and we're going to give it a tool, the Python REPL tool.
和以前一样，我们将给它一个工具，Python REPL工具。
A REPL is basically a way to interact with code.
REPL 基本上是一种与代码交互的方式。
You can think of it as a Jupyter notebook.
你可以把它想象成一个Jupyter笔记本。
The agent can execute code with this REPL.
代理可以使用此 REPL 执行代码。
It's going to run, and then we'll get back some results,
它将运行，然后我们会得到一些结果，
and those results will be passed back into the agent
这些结果将传递回代理
so it can decide what to do next.
这样它就可以决定下一步该做什么。
The problem that we're going to have this agent solve is we're going to give it
我们要让这个代理解决的问题是我们要给它
a list of names and then ask it to sort them.
名称列表，然后要求它对它们进行排序。
You can see here we have a list of names, Harrison Chase,
你可以在这里看到我们有一个名字列表，哈里森蔡斯，
LangChain, LLM, Jeff Fusion, Transformer, Gen AI.
LangChain，LLM，Jeff Fusion，Transformer，Gen AI。
We're going to ask the agent to first sort these names by last name
我们将要求代理首先按姓氏对这些名称进行排序
and then first name and then print the output.
然后命名，然后打印输出。
Importantly, we're asking it to print the output so that it can actually see
重要的是，我们要求它打印输出，以便它可以实际看到
what the result is.
结果是什么。
These printed statements are what's going to be fed back into the language model
这些打印的语句将被反馈到语言模型中
later on so it can reason about the output of the code that it just ran.
稍后，它可以推理它刚刚运行的代码的输出。
Let's give this a try.
让我们试一试。
We can see that when we go into the agent executor chain,
我们可以看到，当我们进入代理执行器链时，
it first realizes that it can use the sorted function to list the customers.
它首先意识到它可以使用排序功能来列出客户。
It's using a different agent type under the hood, which is why you can see
它在引擎盖下使用不同的代理类型，这就是为什么您可以看到
that the action and action input is actually formatted slightly differently.
操作和操作输入的格式实际上略有不同。
Here, the action that it takes is to use the Python REPL,
在这里，它采取的操作是使用 Python REPL，
and then the action input that you can see is code,
然后你可以看到的操作输入是代码，
where it first writes out customers equals this list.
它首先写出客户的位置等于此列表。
It then sorts the customers, and then it goes through this list and prints it.
然后，它对客户进行排序，然后浏览此列表并打印出来。
You can see the agent thinks about what to do and realizes that it needs
您可以看到代理考虑该怎么做并意识到它需要
to write some code.
编写一些代码。
The format that it's using of action and action input is actually slightly
它使用的动作和动作输入的格式实际上略有
different than before.
与以前不同。
It's using a different agent type under the hood.
它在引擎盖下使用不同的代理类型。
For the action, it's going to use the Python REPL, and for the action input,
对于操作，它将使用 Python REPL，对于操作输入，
it's going to have a bunch of code.
它将有一堆代码。
If we look at what this code is doing, it's first creating a variable
如果我们看看这段代码在做什么，它首先创建一个变量。
to list out these customer names.
以列出这些客户名称。
It's then sorting that and creating a new variable, and it's then iterating
然后它对其进行排序并创建一个新变量，然后迭代
through that new variable and printing out each line, just like we asked it to.
通过这个新变量并打印出每一行，就像我们要求的那样。
We can see that we get the observation back, and this is a list of names,
我们可以看到我们得到了观察结果，这是一个名称列表，
and then the agent realizes that it's done, and it returns these names.
然后代理意识到它已完成，并返回这些名称。
We can see from the stuff that's printed out the high level of what's going on,
我们可以从打印出来的东西中看到正在发生的事情的高层次，
but let's dig a little bit deeper and run this with LangChain debug
但是让我们更深入地挖掘并使用LangChain调试运行它
set to true.
设置为 true。
As this prints out all the levels of all the different chains that are going on,
由于这会打印出正在发生的所有不同链的所有级别，
let's go through them and see what exactly is happening.
让我们来看看它们，看看到底发生了什么。
First, we start with the agent executor.
首先，我们从代理执行者开始。
This is the top level agent runner, and we can see that we have here our input.
这是顶级代理运行程序，我们可以看到我们这里有我们的输入。
Sort these customers by last name and then first name and print the output.
按姓氏对这些客户进行排序，然后按名字排序并打印输出。
From here, we call an LLM chain.
从这里开始，我们称之为LLM链。
This is the LLM chain that the agent is using.
这是代理正在使用的LLM链。
The LLM chain, remember, is a combination of prompt and an LLM.
请记住，LLM链是提示和LLM的组合。
At this point, it's only got the input, an agent scratchpad--we'll get back to that
在这一点上，它只有输入，一个代理暂存器 - 我们将回到那个
later--and then some stop sequences to tell the language model when to stop
稍后 - 然后一些停止序列来告诉语言模型何时停止
doing its generations.
做它的世代。
At the next level, we see the exact call to the language model.
在下一个级别，我们看到了对语言模型的确切调用。
We can see the fully formatted prompt, which includes instructions about what
我们可以看到完全格式化的提示，其中包括有关什么的说明
tools it has access to as well as how to format its output.
它有权访问的工具以及如何格式化其输出。
From there, we can then see the exact output of the language model.
从那里，我们可以看到语言模型的确切输出。
We can see the text key where it has the thought and the action and the acronym
我们可以看到文本键，其中包含思想，动作和首字母缩略词
put all in one string.
将所有内容放在一个字符串中。
It then wraps up the LLM chain as it exits through there.
然后，当LLM链通过那里退出时，它会包裹它。
The next thing that it calls is a tool.
它调用的下一件事是一个工具。
Here, we can see the exact input to the tool.
在这里，我们可以看到该工具的确切输入。
We can also see the name of the tool, Python REPL, and then we can see the
我们还可以看到工具的名称，Python REPL，然后我们可以看到
input, which is this code.
输入，即此代码。
We can then see the output of this tool, which is this printed out string.
然后我们可以看到这个工具的输出，即这个打印出来的字符串。
Again, this happens because we specifically ask the Python REPL to print out
同样，发生这种情况是因为我们特别要求Python REPL打印出来。
what is going on.
这是怎么回事。
We can then see the next input to the LLM chain, which again, the LLM chain here
然后我们可以看到LLM链的下一个输入，再次，LLM链在这里
is the agent.
是代理。
Here, if you look at the variables, there's the input.
在这里，如果你看一下变量，就会发现输入。
This is unchanged.
这是不变的。
This is the high-level objective that we're asking.
这是我们要求的高级目标。
Now, there's some new values for agent scratchpad.
现在，代理暂存器有一些新值。
You can see here that this is actually a combination of the previous generation
你可以在这里看到，这实际上是上一代的组合
plus the tool output.
加上工具输出。
We're passing this back in so that the language model can understand what
我们将其传递回去，以便语言模型可以理解什么
happened previously and use that to reason about what to do next.
以前发生过，并用它来推理下一步该做什么。
The next few print statements are covering what happens as the language model
接下来的几个打印语句将涵盖语言模型发生的情况
realizes that it is basically finished with its job.
意识到它基本上完成了它的工作。
We can see here the fully formatted prompt to the language model, the response,
我们可以在这里看到语言模型的完全格式化提示，响应，
where it realizes that it is done, and it says final answer, which here is the
它意识到它已经完成了，它说最终答案，这里是
sequence that the agent uses to recognize that it's done with its job.
代理用于识别其已完成作业的序列。
We can then see it exiting the LLM chain and then exiting the agent executor.
然后我们可以看到它退出 LLM 链，然后退出代理执行器。
This should hopefully give you a pretty good idea of what's going on under the
这应该希望能让你很好地了解下面发生了什么
hood inside these agents.
这些代理内部的罩子。
This should hopefully give you a pretty good idea of what's going on under the
这应该希望能让你很好地了解下面发生了什么
hood and is hopefully instructive as you pause and put your own objectives for
胡德，希望对您暂停并制定自己的目标具有指导意义
this coding agent to try to accomplish.
尝试完成此编码代理。
This debug mode can also be used to highlight what's going wrong.
此调试模式还可用于突出显示出错的原因。
As shown above in the Wikipedia example, sometimes agents act a little funny,
如上面的维基百科示例所示，有时代理表现得有点滑稽，
and so having all this information is really helpful for understanding what's
因此，拥有所有这些信息对于理解什么是非常有帮助的
going on.
继续。
So far, we've used tools that come defined in Language Chain already.
到目前为止，我们已经使用了语言链中定义的工具。
But a big power of agents is that you can connect it to your own sources of
但是代理的一大力量是你可以把它连接到你自己的来源
information, your own APIs, your own data.
信息、您自己的 API、您自己的数据。
So here, we're going to go over how you can create a custom tool so that you
所以在这里，我们将介绍如何创建自定义工具，以便
can connect it to whatever you want.
可以将其连接到您想要的任何内容。
Let's make a tool that's going to tell us what the current date is.
让我们制作一个工具，告诉我们当前日期是什么。
First, we're going to import this tool decorator.
首先，我们将导入此工具装饰器。
This can be applied to any function, and it turns it into a tool that
这可以应用于任何功能，并将其变成一个工具
Lang Chain can use.
郎链可以使用。
Next, we're going to write a function called time, which takes in any text
接下来，我们将编写一个名为 time 的函数，它接收任何文本
string.
字符串。
We're not really going to use that, and it's going to return today's date by
我们不会真正使用它，它将返回今天的日期
calling date time.
呼叫日期时间。
In addition to the name of the function, we're also going to write a really
除了函数的名称，我们还将编写一个
detailed doc string.
详细的文档字符串。
That's because this is what the agent will use to know when it should call this
那是因为这是代理将用来知道何时应该调用它的内容
tool and how it should call this tool.
工具以及它应该如何调用此工具。
For example, here we say that the input should always be an empty string.
例如，这里我们说输入应该始终是一个空字符串。
That's because we don't use it.
那是因为我们不使用它。
If we have more stringent requirements on what the input should be, for
如果我们对输入应该是什么有更严格的要求，对于
example, if we have a function that should always take in a search query or a
例如，如果我们有一个函数，它应该始终接受搜索查询或
SQL statement, you'll want to make sure to mention that here.
SQL 语句，您需要确保在此处提及。
We're now going to create another agent.
我们现在将创建另一个代理。
This time, we're adding the time tool to the list of existing tools.
这一次，我们将时间工具添加到现有工具列表中。
And finally, let's call the agent and ask it what the date today is.
最后，让我们打电话给代理商，问它今天的日期是什么。
It recognizes that it needs to use the time tool, which it specifies here.
它认识到它需要使用它在此处指定的时间工具。
It has the action input as an empty string.
它将操作输入作为空字符串。
This is great.
这太好了。
This is what we told it to do.
这就是我们告诉它要做的。
And then it returns with an observation, and then finally, the language model
然后它返回一个观察结果，最后是语言模型
takes that observation and responds to the user.
获取该观察结果并响应用户。
Today's date is 2023-05-21.
今天的日期是 2023-05-21。
You should pause the video here and try putting in different inputs.
您应该在此处暂停视频并尝试输入不同的输入。
This wraps up the lesson on agents.
关于代理的课程到此结束。
This is one of the newer and more exciting and more experimental pieces of
这是更新，更令人兴奋，更具实验性的作品之一
LangChain, so I hope you enjoy using it.
LangChain，所以我希望你喜欢使用它。
Hopefully, it showed you how you can use a language model as a reasoning
希望它向您展示了如何使用语言模型作为推理
engine to take different actions and connect to other functions and data
引擎采取不同的操作并连接到其他功能和数据
sources.
来源。
soon.
很快。